Preliminary Guide to the Collection of Canadian Bookplates
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Canadian Bookplates
1800-1924
BKP 78
Yale University Arts Library
0.42
(1 box)
This collection comprises mostly 19th- and early 20th-century Canadian bookplates.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011 it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection comprises mostly 19th- and early 20th-century Canadian bookplates. It includes both private bookplates as well as institutional ones. Among the artists represented are the following: William Walker Alexander, W. J. Beattie, Stanley Harrod, J. E. H. MacDonald, and Arthur Howard Noll.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Bookplates – Individuals. II. Bookplates – Institutions. III. Bookplates from a scrapbook.
Bookplates, Canadian; Bookplates
- Bookplates – Individuals, Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains private bookplates arranged alphabetically by the patron's last name.
  - Abbott – Chaussé, 1911-1924 undated; 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Connor – Harrison, 1897-1921 undated; 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Harrod – Milner, 1901-1921 undated; 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Moore – S., 1905-1911 undated; 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Scadding – Wilson, 1805-1921 undated; 24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified, undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bookplates – Institutions, Series II
  This series contains various library, university, social organization, or business bookplates arranged alphabetically.
  - Art Association of Montreal – Knights Templar (St. Mungo Preceptory), 1851 1911 undated; 17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Club (Toronto) – University of Toronto, circa 1890-1920 undated; 21 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bookplates from a scrapbook, Series III
  - 3 pages from an unidentified scrapbook of bookplates, 1901 1903 undated; 14 bookplates; 1 visiting card; 1 postcard (Box 1, Folder 9)
    These pages were previously removed from an unidentified scrapbook of bookplates. The pages are labeled "Canadian" and inscribed with a number in the upper right corner. Some of the bookplates are individually annotated.